Hello everybody. Welcome to the
September 9th, 2026 finance committee uh
meeting. A couple of housekeeping items.
If you could make sure that your phone
is either on vibrate or muted. Um,
anybody who wants to make public
comment, please approach the podium and
identify yourself and then uh we will
only be discussing the items on the
agenda. Once those meeting or once those
items have been completed, we will
adjourn the finance committee meeting.
With that, Jen, I will turn it over to
you. Number 6A, application for transfer
of location and ownership of retail
liquor license filed with the city
clerk's office for Capital City
Hospitality LLC doing business as
Wyoming Discount Liquor 3501 East
Lincoln Way, Cheyenne, Wyoming. License
currently held by 1734 Partners LLC,
1734 Meadow Land Drive, Cheyenne,
Wyoming.
>> Staff report, please.
>> Members of the committee, Kylie Soden,
city clerk. The item before you is an
application for a transfer of location
and ownership of retail liquor license
submitted by Capital City Hospitality
LLC doing business as Wyoming Discount
Liquor to be located at 3501 East
Lincolnway. The liquor license is
currently held by 1734 Partners LLC
located at 1734 Mealand Drive. The
application has been reviewed by
applicable city departments and the
Wyoming Liquor Division and requirements
for the application have been met. I can
answer any questions you may have.
>> Any questions for staff?
Hearing none. Thank you, Kylie. Hearing
none, we will go out to uh the public
for public comment.
Welcome, sir.
>> Welcome. Thank you. Um I'm John Johnson.
I'm representing Capitol City
Hospitality. Um we purchased the Big
Lots building. I recognize you guys from
a couple weeks ago.
>> [clears throat]
>> We purchased the Big Lots building down
there at 3501 um East Lincoln Way. And
we're looking to move this license to
that location and put in a um
I'm going to call it a multi-enue. It's
going to have a retail liquor store.
It's going to have a restaurant and
potentially an OTB or offtrack vetting
uh venue. So, I brought some things with
me, but they were the same ones I gave
to you the other day other than the menu
for Wyoming Works. Uh, so if you would
like to see those, I'd be glad to hand
that out into you. Um, but the other
thing was just the floor plan that you
all saw the other night. So,
and I'm here for any questions if you
have any.
>> Any questions for Mr. Johnson?
>> Well, thank you for being here, sir, and
we uh we look forward to uh the
possibilities that uh your project
or is putting before us. So,
>> thank you. Thank you.
>> Thank you. Any other comments from the
public?
hearing. None. Do I have a motion from
the committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, um I move uh to approve.
>> A second.
>> It's been moved and approved. Uh any
comments from the from the committee
hearing? None. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> Opposed.
That item uh was I unanimously. So uh
there is no opposition. That item will
move forward. Next item, please.
>> Number 9D. Contract between the city of
Cheyenne, Office of Youth Alternatives,
and Laramie County to provide services
to the Larmy County Juvenile Crisis
Shelter.
>> Staff report.
Amber, you wanna
This has been an item for as long as I
can remember, so I know it's something
we do each and every year. Um, chair
through you. I do know um that youth
alternatives um is responding or has
been responding this week um to a
situation at one of the schools um and
so certainly I can take any questions or
concerns you may have and follow up
accordingly.
Mr. Chairman,
>> committee members, this is Jay Sullivan,
the director of youth alternatives. I
think I was just let in as a as a
panelist. Um, can you hear me? Okay,
>> we can, sir. Go ahead, Jay.
>> Awesome. Thank you, Amber. Thank you for
uh filling in. Um the item before the uh
the committee is a a standing contract
that we've had with the council uh to
provide uh crisis center uh counseling
services uh to youth being placed out
there. This is a contract in the amount
of $95,799
uh as revenue to the city. And I'll
stand by for any questions.
>> Any questions or comments for Mr.
Sullivan? Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I don't have a
question, but I do have a comment. Um, I
work uh real close with Youth
Alternatives through the Juvenile
Justice Joint Powers Board, and this is
a critical um asset to our community,
and I think we're incredibly lucky to
have them um on our team. So, I would
definitely support this action.
>> Thank you, Dr. Emmens.
Anyone else?
Hearing none, let's go out to the public
for public comment.
Nope.
All right. Do I have a motion from the
committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
in the amount not to exceed the ma the
amount of $95,799.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Comments
from the committee
hearing. None. I just want to echo what
my colleague said. Uh Mr. Sullivan,
we're very lucky to have youth
alternatives in our community and you
all have been making a difference uh in
the lives of kids for as long as I can
remember. So, keep up the great work.
>> Um,
>> chairman, committee members, thank you
so much for your your continued support.
So,
>> with that, uh, all those in favor of the
contract, please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> No one's opposed. That item moves
forward. Next item, please.
>> Number 9 C. Contract between the city of
Cheyenne, Office of Youth Alternatives,
and Larmy County to provide probation
diversion services to youth appearing in
both the Laramie County Circuit Court
and the Municipal Court.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chairman, committee members, Jay
Sullivan, director of youth
alternatives. Once again, uh this uh is
a long-standing contract that we've had
with the county to provide uh diversion
and probation services to our youth uh
coming through the court system. Uh this
is in the amount of $86,34
uh as revenue to the city. I'll stand by
for any questions.
>> Any comments or questions for Mr.
Sullivan?
>> Hearing none, let's go out to the
public. Any comments by members of the
public
hearing? None. Do I have a motion by
from the committee?
>> Uh, Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the
bid in the amount not to exceed the
amount of $86,34.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Any
comments from the committee?
>> Hearing none. All those in favor of this
contract, please signify by saying I.
>> I. No one's opposed. That item moves
forward. Next item, please.
>> Number 9 F, professional services
agreement between the city of Cheyenne
and Houseel Lavine Associates LLC for
the Cheyenne next comprehensive plan
update.
Staff report.
>> Chairman and committee Charles Bloom,
Planning and Development Director. Um,
this is a much recently discussed update
to our comprehensive plan. Um what we
have prepared is a contract with Hel
Lavine. They're a national planning firm
that's located um and based out of
Chicago, Illinois. We do have Nick Davis
who is on the Zoom call. Um so if we
could promote him, that would be perfect
because he'll give a little quick update
on what they propose to do. Um this is a
contract that uh is not to exceed the
dollar amount of $351,790.
Um what this uh does is this would
provide a 14-month uh time frame for us
to have our comprehensive plan
evaluated, updated and ready and
adopted. Um with this uh with this plan,
we have a a base uh service which is
update the plan and we have a couple of
different add-ons that have been
incorporated in this negotiated price.
Those specific add-ons are number one um
using Placer AI data to identify and
recognize commuting trends that we have
in our community. Um a lot of that data
is anticipated to identify where are
construction workers coming from in the
community. Are they coming from northern
Colorado? Are they coming from the
community? Are they coming from uh
cities in the region? Um the second item
is to do land use scenario planning
which is going to specifically look at
um the land use plan and different types
of scenarios. Um one of our biggest
items of concern and biggest items of
debate at planning commission and at
council have been the land use plan
amendments for industrial uses. So the
scenario planning is going to look at
different scenarios and um identify what
would it look like if there was a uh
restrictions on data centers in certain
areas if there was anything goes type of
philosophy and and stuff like that. Um
that analysis will look at revenue
opportunities uh the effect on housing
um among some other items. Um that exact
framework will be defined uh through
that process. Um, I've opened any
questions you may have on this uh
contract and uh Nick Davis is online and
can provide some more details on behalf
of Household Lavine.
>> Comments from the committee. Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. I just have a
question. Can they do it quicker than 14
months?
>> Chair through you two, Dr. Emmens.
That's a great question. The initial
proposal was to have it complete in 18
months. Um in working with them uh we
negotiated a 14month uh review. So we
moved it up by 4 months. Um that is what
the resources had allowed but yes we
understand um the urgency.
>> Mr. Wolf.
>> Uh and Mr. Chairman, thank you very much
through you. Um just two quick comments.
Uh first of all, Mr. Bloom, thank you
and your staff for the work you did last
night. The planning commission a um a
lot of evidence of thoughtful and hard
work uh on behalf of the community. So,
thanks for that. And second of all, um I
just to thank you for what has obviously
been a just the analysis part of putting
this whole contract together and
figuring out, you know, both the scope
of the work and the timing of the work.
Um and um we would like to hear from the
consultant as well. Um what happens at
the end of that 14month period? Does
does that does that plan then come back
to the council for approval on your
recommendations or how how does that
actually get uh into effect?
>> Mr. Bloom
and chair, members of the committee. Um
that's a great question regarding how
this works. Um throughout this process
there is a lot of uh public engagement
that will occur. There's engagement with
the public. There'll be engagement with
the steering committee and there'll also
be um work sessions with the the
governing body. There'll be several of
those that are included. Um the the goal
under the contract is to have a final uh
comprehensive plan update document uh
ready um pretty much at the end of the
14 months for adoption by the governing
body. Um there are a couple of nuances
under state statute we will have to
follow um regarding concurrence with the
county commissioners and such since this
will likely involve lands outside the um
incor incorporated limits of the city.
Um but that will be the goal. Uh with
the plan, we hope that the plan will be
something that pretty much everybody is
behind um by the time we bring it
forward for adoption. There'll be draft
reviews, there'll be opportunities for
public comment. Uh we'll be able to
identify, you know, where those concerns
lie. Um so we can hopefully have all of
those addressed by the time it makes it
to this point. Um, the last thing we
want to do is send forward a plan that
is a complete surprise and doesn't look
like anything that that we've all been
working on over the course of the 14
months.
>> Thank you, Mr. Wolf.
Any other comments or questions for Mr.
Bloom?
>> I do have one.
>> Dr. Emmens.
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Um, will the
consultant coordinate all the public
input processes or will your office have
to do that?
>> Chair, members of committee, uh, Dr.
Um, I'll let the consultant correct me
if I'm incorrect, but I know I know that
as part of the cost savings um to bring
that price down uh to get to that
14-month period and also incorporate
some of the add-ons at a lesser um rate.
We will kind of both be tag teaming
that. They have some public engagement
um items that they will be facilitating
online. um they will be uh present for a
couple of public engagement type
sessions, but they're also providing us
what is uh called a it's a toolkit for
popup workshops and public engagement
activities. So, we can do those on more
smaller scales. So, it really will be
kind of a hybrid. It'll be both. And
I'll let Mr. Davis provide any
additional details on that public
engagement.
>> Yeah,
>> Mr. Davis.
>> Oh, sorry. Can you hear me? Just want to
make sure
>> we can, sir. Go ahead.
>> All right. Well, first of all, thank you
so much for giving us an opportunity to
u meet with your your finance committee
this morning. Um the or this afternoon,
I suppose. Uh the engagement side is a
fairly robust approach. So, we have a
lot of different avenues and how we're
going to engage the community at
different stages through the project. Um
up front, we'll do these stakeholder
interviews and we'll have um discussions
with focus groups. There's going to be
some community like public kickoffs.
We'll we'll be facilitating those
discussions, but working with staff. Um,
you know, they'll help us get the word
out, the message out. Um, there'll be
some things that we'll sort of, you
know, as as was mentioned, we'll be
sharing the burden or the time on. Um,
but our team will always be summarizing
those events and those activities and
incorporating those into not just our
summary of outreach, but also the
existing conditions as that's all
getting pulled together. Uh, and then
throughout the rest of the process,
we'll be meeting with um the public and
stakeholders just to do check-ins and
make sure that we're on track and we're
developing the plans, policies um that's
in line with what the community wants to
see.
>> Thank you. Any other comments or
questions?
>> Hold on, Mr. Bloom. Uh with hearing
none, we'll go out to the public.
Comments or questions from members of
the public?
hearing none. Do I have a motion from
the committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to approve in the
the contract in the amount not to exceed
the amount of $351,790.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Comments
from the committee
hearing none. All those in favor, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> No one's opposed. That item will move
forward. Next item, please.
>> Number 9G, grant award agreement between
the city of Cheyenne and the Wyoming
Office of Homeland Security for the
fiscal year 2025 state homeland security
program.
>> Welcome, Captain James.
>> Chair, members of the committee, Captain
James, Shy Police Department, what you
have before you is a grant award
agreement for approval. This is from the
State Homeland Security Program or SHSP
um program that we are um looking at
receiving. Well, we've already uh
received the grant, but uh $142,800
and the plans for this is to purchase 26
vests and accessories for our SWAT team.
Our current vests have been expired for
two years and uh this this new system
will uh will be much more user friendly.
Can I stand for any questions?
>> Thank you, Captain. Comments or
questions for Captain James?
Hearing none, do I have comments or
questions from the public? Hearing
none. Do I have a motion from the
committee?
>> Uh, I move to approve in the amount not
to exceed $142,800.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Comments
or questions from the committee
hearing? None. All those in favor,
please signify by saying I. I.
>> No one's opposed. That item will move
forward. Next item, please.
Number 11B, consideration of bid number
S-1-27
for a contract between the city of
Cheyenne and STC Construction Company
Incorporated for the Cahill and Lions
Park pavement restoration project.
>> Mr. Sanchez,
>> Mr. Chair, Jason Sanchez, Community
Wreck and Events. Before you and for
your consideration is the bid between
the city and STC for the pavement um
improvements at Cahill and Lions Park.
Uh the funding for this was approved
during the budget and our goal if we
have your support today is to have the
projects completed by October 31st of
this year. I'll stand for any questions,
comments or questions for Mr. Sanchez.
Just uh just one point of clarification.
Uh Jason, did you say it would be
completed this year? But
>> Mr. Chair, that's correct. Wow,
>> that's really good news. Thank you. Um,
there are no comments or questions for
Mr. Sanchez. We'll go out to the public.
Uh, questions or comments from members
of the public.
>> Hearing none. Do I have a motion from
the committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the bid
in the amount not to exceed $647,15410.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Comments
or questions from the committee? Hearing
none. All those in favor of this big
consideration, please signify by saying
I.
>> I.
>> No one's opposed. That item will move
forward. Next item.
>> Number 11 C. Consideration to purchase
between the city of Cheyenne and
Motorola
Solutions Absolute Solutions
Incorporated for the purchase of
Motorola portable mobile and base
station radios for the animal control
division.
staff report.
>> Good afternoon, Mr. Chairman, committee
members. What you have before you today
is a request. Um, we have radios that
have failed, that have aged out of the
system, which we were unaware of,
otherwise we'd have placed that in our
budget request. Um, found this out when
they decided not to come on one
afternoon. Uh, so we're on cell phones,
folks, uh, dispatching from cell phones
and and working that way. So, the
request is for $94,84722.
This will replace the base station. It
allows replace all the handhelds and the
uh radios within the trucks. And I would
stand for questions.
>> Questions for Mr. Fountain.
>> Eric, I have a question. How old are
those current radios that are no longer
working?
>> Mr. Chairman, I think they're they're
from the animal shelter when they had
the services. So, they're at least 5
years old. Um, I think they're way older
than that, though, because Motorola was
very clear with us. We took the base
station in after I started smoking and
said, "Hey, can you guys look at this
and tell us what's wrong with it?" it
and they're like, "What is that?" And
and so it became very clear that what we
had was a an antique, if you will. Um
hope it has a value in a pawn shop
somewhere someday.
>> Great. Well, thank you for that. Uh we
appreciate all the hard work you and
your staff do. Um any questions or Dr.
Emmens?
>> Thank you, Mr. Chairman. Eric, does that
include the installation or is that just
the purchase of the radios?
>> Mr. Chairman, through you it uh it does
all of it. So, Mr. Bottlebort helped us
out with that and uh without him, I
probably would have had a bigger mess
and been back here again, but TJ did a
fantastic job and helping us navigate
that. So, it'll take care of all of it.
>> Thank you. Uh any comments or questions
from the public?
>> Mr. Chairman, just real quick before you
make the motions on these, these should
be to approve. I know that the report
says accept the purchase, but the motion
would be to approve in the amount.
Thank you, Jen, for that correction.
We will make note of that language.
If there are no comments or questions
from members of the public, do I have a
motion from the committee?
Mr. Chairman, um I move to approve the
purchase in an amount not to exceed
$94,84722.
Second. Sorry.
>> Okay. It's been moved and seconded.
Comments from the committee.
Hearing none. All those in favor of this
consideration to purchase, please
signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> No one's opposed. That item will move
forward. Next item, please.
>> Number 11D. consideration to purchase
between the city of Cheyenne and
Motorola Solutions Bearcom for the
purchase of Motorola
mobile radios for the Cheyenne Police
Department.
>> Staff report.
>> Mr. Chair, members of the committee,
Captain David James, Cheyenne Police
Department. Uh what you have before you
is a consideration of purchase for 10
mobile radios for our 10 new squad cars
that we've recently ordered. Uh this is
a sole source purchase from Motorola
Solutions as Motorola is the only radio
that works with Wolink. Um, so we're
very limited on on what we can use. So
this is a total amount of $82,20
and in memory of Councilman Royel, 80
cents. And I stand for any questions.
>> I will always think of uh, former
Councilman Royel whenever I see cents
uh, after an amount. Um, any comments or
questions for Captain James?
Hearing none, do we have any comments or
questions from members of the public?
Hearing
none. Do I have a motion from the
committee?
>> Mr. Chairman, I move to accept the
purchase. Accept the purchase. Approve
the purchase in an amount not to exceed
$82,2080.
>> Second.
>> It's been moved and seconded. Comments
from the committee
hearing none. All those in favor of this
uh purch uh purchase consideration,
please signify by saying I.
>> I.
>> No one's opposed. That I moves forward
and that completes our agenda. As such,
this meeting is adjourned. Thank you
all.